Tarun Pant

Contact No: 8608777416

Permanent Address: Email: tarunpant26@hotmail.com

Nawabi Road Haldwani (Nainital) Uttarakhand-263139

SUMMARY:

7.5 years of experience in IT Industry. Currently working with Coforge (Advantage Go) as a Senior Software Engineer. Highly motivated with an excellent communication and Inter-personal skills, flexible and versatile to new environments, self-motivated a good team player, tech-savvy professional and have worked in multicultural environment. Looking for a new motivated corporate environment for better prospects and growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLSSET:

- ➤ Having experience in C#, ASP.NET MVC, .Net Core, Web API, JavaScript, Angular
- ➤ Microsoft SQL Server
- ➤ VSTS, TFS

LANGUAGES:

➤ Primarily C#

CERTIFICATIONS:

- > AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- ➤ AZ-204 Microsoft Azure Developer Associate

EDUCATION:

- > B.Tech from Uttarakhand Technical University in ECE (2009-2013) with 76.3%
- ➤ 12th from H.N Inter College with 79.3%
- ➤ 10th from B.B.V.M Inter College with 81%

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Coforge (Advantage Go) (Dec 2020 - Current)

#1 PROJECT NAME: Underwriting

ROLE: Senior Software Engineer

DESCRIPTION:

It is a centralized insurance platform called Underwriting which and delivers analytics-driven insights throughout the decision-making process, it is Powered by an ecosystem of data providers that supports data led decisions, Underwriting proactively delivers new business insights and risk-specific knowledge, and facilitates the creation of new products, and enables underwriters to understand risk at new levels of granularity.

TECHNOLOGIES/TOOLS:

Visual Studio 2019, MS SQL Server 2017, .Net Core, Web API, Angular

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Requirement Analysis, Product Development, Testing
- > Implementation of features and Sonar issues

Siemens Healthineers (June 2019 – Dec 2020)

#1 PROJECT NAME: AI-Pathway Companion

ROLE: Software Developer

DESCRIPTION:

AI-Pathway companion will be a clinical decision support system based on clinical guideline data imported by artificial intelligence that can aid physicians in making diagnostic and therapeutic decisions along the clinical pathway.

TECHNOLOGIES/TOOLS:

Visual Studio 2017, MS SQL Server 2017, .Net Core 2.2, Web API, Angular

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ➤ Requirement Analysis, Product Development, Testing and Documentation
- > Implementation of features and bug-fixing

ACHIEVEMENTS:

Recognition of efforts and contribution towards achieving code freeze milestone of AI-Pathway Companion VA10A in September 2019 enabling Clinical Use Test in Q1 FY20.

Broadridge Financial Solutions (July 2017- June 2019)

#1 PROJECT NAME: Invoice Allocation

ROLE: Senior Member Technical

DESCRIPTION:

Invoice allocation is financial product by Broadridge Financial Solutions and it helps the clients to generated the invoices and provide better understanding about client's shareholders communication. Involved in design, coding and testing of the product.

TECHNOLOGIES/TOOLS:

Visual Studio 2013, 2015, MS SQL Server 2012/DB2, MVC, Web API

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Involved in designing, coding and testing of the requirements of the project.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

> Recognized by Client for continuous outstanding performance in the development and testing.

Cognizant Technology Solutions (May 2014 - June 2017)

#1 PROJECT NAME: ClaimSphereTM HEDIS® (A Healthcare Product)

ROLE: Program Analyst (Product Engineer)

DESCRIPTION:

ClaimSphereTM HEDIS® system helps health insurance payers gain a deeper understanding of their population, deliver better care and reduce costs. ClaimSphereTM HEDIS® identifies key issues in patient data that impact scores and helps the payers take corrective action to improve the HEDIS® quality rating.

TECHNOLOGIES/TOOLS:

Visual Studio 2013, 2015, MS SQL Server 2012, MVC, Web API, JavaScript, ADO.net

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ➤ Integrated report module.
- > Troubleshooting in the product.

EXTRACURRICULARS:

- > Participated as a volunteer in various kinds of corporate outreach events and functions.
- > Participated in state level science event and various cultural programs in school.

PERSONAL DOSSIER:

- Date of birth: 26 August 1992
- Language known: English, Hindi, Tamil (Beginner)

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.